<topics>

  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-early-battleships</id>
    <results>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062268/1906-02-11/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Battleship+Powerful+Launched+Monster+Dreadnought+England</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Great Naval Achievement
1 h l innc 1 tnaj of the Dreadnought
ar zo i and most 4owerfl battle
1
4 of the vorlds miles marks the
t ire ta what Ui Brfttah admir
laim as the protest acfeteve
i I in naval construction OR Oc
II r 2nd IMG only s few days over
4Ir months age work was commenced
r t smooth oc the vessel the ftrfct
v hat is to i e known ac tin Drent
nunru class The prowise was name
KM gar she would be launched with
in pis months The adwtraity has
IIIOT than mad good their boa t sail
B iti ivrs hare another c He for
pnl n their avy Another twelve
iinifi j ai mine well the Drearl
nvirh is 11 be commissioned and join
i o ViVaic Fleet tows beating all
YOJ i coords ta battleshin build
nv 11 x months There are two rea
MI hv work IB being cashed OR tho
n 1n incjt One is the great say
TU H OS but the chief reason is
1i 10 shin is to some extent Ma est
i t IT dud it is desired to give ker
I 1 trial before commencing COlt
K ion on nay more of hr claws
Watched Japanese Vessels i
r a Britain H wilt be remembered
w 8 11 only power having attaches
or Oliver OR Japanese skiPs dtt i
r t 11 RussoJaMeee war while
fIl Hr lish eonstmciors were given
I vppurumity of l arain where
N snips of J4 pall proved weak or
nilg ai the case might be Thee
n wre busy from start to finish i
lit war and immediately after the t
V I f the Sad Japan came home I
a 1 heir data which was submitted
n h MggcstkMus to a special commit
011 w itch sat not only the most ex
nc d naval expens but the direc
f of naval construct Lord Kel 1
tn iud a Bimiber of the leading pri
iill ship builders The Doa ught
It h 0 outcome of their deliberations
m odimeat of the lessons of the hue
a in the Far Bast a ship aparently
lminoie capable at one discharge of
htir rims of throwing with uaparallel
rf fvre twice as much mHal as any
firp m raaaofwar mow afloat while
h r armor will render her immune
f m aarks bjr any eusmys guns
any s afr claim e eII i against torpe
does fired at tile naval battle range
Detains A Secret j
TJ ri tails of the Dreadnoughts con
11 n remain a ecm 90 w U has
Imiralty panted the plans Ef
of naval attaches to gather in
e i n for their governments haven
n niitless No information is
f wing the answer to all eaquir
1 sing the candid one that Great
T
tin intends to maintain secrecy as
j v hat her experts learned as A re
o Japans experiences for one
md by roshing to completion the
T dnought will gain a year if not
11 in naval constraction over all
powers except her ally TJsnal
1 5 11 n ships are building a board Is
1 at the head of the slip giv
Tier name displacement priwci
p2 dimensions horse power and
2 In the case of the Oreadnotrcfet
r an item in tie design is reveal
11n board containing the simpte
1 1 once His Majestys Ship Dread
111 commenced October ad1
lt C When ready for sea the ship
r splnce 15M tons but this is
n 1e t remarkable thing about her
r I 1wid the ideas introduced as a
r n t of the Far Eastern war Britain
IE 1 acnR on her new fighting machine
h f hcaiest armament ever carried
bra hip Ia the pact British vessels
p attend four 12inca guns throw
ill u puand shells the Dr ad
ar 1ht will have tea of these weapons</text>
      </result>
      
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1906-02-22/ed-1/?sp=3&q=England+Englands+Monster+Battleship+Battle-ship+Giant+Connecticut+Sea+Fighter</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Englands Greatest Sea Fighter Is Somewhat
Larger but the Yankee Ship Has a
I
Greater Zone of Action
The Dreadnought Just launched in England is the largest battleship
afloat and In actital fighting force the most powerful
If she were to meet the Connecticut the latest product of Amorlcnn
uaval architecture the difference In weight of metal and bulk as well as
speed might well be made up by the superior efuclency of the American
ship which has a larger zone ofac tlon a superiority of ordnance and a
greater armor thus following the traditions of the American navy
I
r vi
DREADNOUGHT THE LARGER
CONNECTICUT MORE ACTIVE
Connecticut Dreadnought</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062268/1906-03-21/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Admiral+Dewey+Giant+Battleships+Vessels+War+Navy</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Washington Mar 20Great bat
tleships like the eighteen thousand
ton English battleship Dreadnought I
are the crying need of the American
I navy according to Admiral George
Dewey who appeared before the
House Committee on Naval Affairs I
today to discuss the future of the
American navy
At least eighteen thousand ton bat
tleships with ten twelve inch guns
i each should be authorized at once in
Admiral Deweys opinion He would
have these of American design and
thinks we should be creative rather
than imitative in developing the
navy
VAdr
Adr iral Dewey also beHeves in ex
tensive experiments with submarine
boats</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1906-04-08/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Powerful+Battleship+England+Dreadnought+Fighting+Ships+Navy</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>THE British battleship Dreadnought,
4 launched from Portsmouth dock
yard by the King on February 10.
marks a notable advance in naval
design. It is not, of course, revo
lutionary, as was the French La Glolre
of 1857 or the American Monitor of 18C2.
The type is as clearly evolved from the
Lord Nelson class as that' class is derived
from the King Edward VII group. But,
new departure/or not, no ship of war
has since the advent of the La plolre—
now historically famous as the first sea
going ironclad— and of 'the Monitor
aroused so much technical interest and
excited so much public curiosity.
It is at this stage impossible to describe
•with exactness all the elements of the
DTeadnough't's design, for its secrets have
been kept with such, admirable close
ness that t the facts are known only to
a limited circle. Even so eminent a critic
as Sir William White, late chief con
structor ;of the^Brltlsh navy, seems to
have based an! adverse 'opinion of the type
on wrong assumptions and \it\u25a0: is safe \u25a0to
cay with the London' Engineer, If a: per-
Bon of hl« enormous experience could be
led into error, how less likely Is it that
the opinions and deductions of lefser
lights will prove correct It xnay there
fore be well to add that the general de
scription of the Dreadnought "has been
taken from conservative i and apparently
reliable accounts that have appeared In
such trustworthy; Journals^ as the En
gineer and Engineering of .London and
the i: Naval and Military Record of
Plymouth.
.During, the five months that the Dread
nought has been "under construction suf
ficient truth has,' however,^ been whispered
to prove that the new ship Is an incorpo-
?HE V- SAN FRANCISCO/^SUNDAY^ CALL;
ratlonof ideas, some suggested and some,
older and evolutionary, confirmed by the
results of the Russo-Japanese sea war.
It is fairly, well t known, for example,'
that the vessel is to possess an enormous
concentration sof offensive and "defensive
energies through the installation "*l. of a
main battery of v 12-Inch guns, that the
usual intermediate battery.- 1 has been
eliminated, -that: the Babcock-Wilcox
.water tube boilers are to develop J 23,000
horsepower,^ and that the turbine engines
are expected to give an average sea' speed
of twenty/or twenty-one knotsJ The ax
mor protection is to Ibe distributed tover
a large area and ito thick v enough \u25a0; to
resist the direct impact of 12-lnch projec-'
tiles fired over a range of 3000 yards.^The
ship's underwater, body is to be arranged
so i as" to^ furnish Vaj reasonable -immunity,
from automatic torpedoes i and fixed j or'
floating, mines. 'One further adyantagei is
the gain in; fighting 'simplificatlonr- due" to
the single class v and the uniform service
of the; ammunition '.needed.;:,'
So far ;'as the jusiial technical data it "is stated*, by; London Engineering
the Dreadnought is 500 feet long," 82 feet in
beam and'-at a displacement of 18,000 tons
will; draw 26 if eet l of water. The] boilers
are 'of the Babcock ;"Wilcox type, ;,with
a pressure of 250 pounds: there. are four
propell ex shafts, and with a horsepower of
23,000 the speed, wilU be about .twenty-one*
knots. Apart. from the novel feature, found
in the abolition of the? secondary arma
ment, there fare several other notable de-^
partures from accepted design. Two stern
posts and two rudders, placed some' twen
ty feet apart.V are provided. .The ten
twelve-inch guns *of the main armament
are? arranged ''in -three barbettes, each
mounting a pair of guns on the 1 keel line,
one on the poop/ one abaft the funnels
and one on the high forecastle., The other
two pairs will be in, hooded barbettes, lo
cated on either; bow, so that the I fire
ahead will be from'- six guns, the fire
astern from two and on the broadside
from no less than. eight. -This, is a very
great gain indeed, for there can be small
doubt that broadside Is far more; im
portant «than end-on fire. The -Dread
nought will, when heed arises, -be a good
ship Z in a chase; her stern fire is, of
course,'. weak, but then she. is not likely to
be found showing her stern" to anything
that floats. The torpedo defense gun rls
now, spoken of as an cighteen-pounder,
but? they number -to be mounted; is not
Btated." -T '\u25a0..- ',h ''\u25a0\u25a0\u25a0\u25a0*'\u25a0 .-.'.'\u25a0\u25a0.'\u25a0.>
It is, however, claimed; In: other, quar
ters that the f oregolng_dJsposition of the
main armament is not accurate, \u25a0 and .that
the twelve-inch 'guns (45-callber in' length)
are 'to'; be mounted level on the upper, i? deck. ITwb- of these
are to be carried in a' forward and two in
lan after' barbette,' situated on the fore
"and aft line of the ship. Three, are to Vbe
mounted each in a i single barbette on
either broadside. This disposition :of .the
big \u25a0 guns is, therefore, a close reproduc-1
tiori of that installed in the Lord Ntlson,
the "onlyj substantial^ changes being the
substitution \u25a0\u25a0 of 12-inch ordnance for, the
9.2-inch i intermediates (of the i earlier' de
sign. .Whichever plan is 'adopted, ;^the
j cumulative effect' of eight guns fired to
gether" in -broadside; must f; be enormous,
and the effect even of a single shot, owing
to 't the great increase in- energy of .these
latest gun '.types, must be most destructive
even at the new, fighting ranges. It should
be kept in mind that future actions will
probably be fought at ranges J so extended
that -\u25a0 only J the heaviest shots j will in any
final sense count. VThe flat the
line' of projected* flight-^can> also; be so
low that no zone of /safety^ will exist with
in effective torpedo. range.'x-rj
v What, It I may asked; r will the Ad-
miralty with '-j aY ship f of this tre
mendous i power wheni she Is'commis
sioned? With .the ten 12-inch guns of
the 'latest 'type opposed Uo -the, four
mounted in; even the bast foreign bat
tleships, she should be equal to any two
vessels now, afloat. In defensive quali
ties she will, thanks to the thickness
and; quality of her armor, ba Immune
from damage by gunfire at ordinary
battle ranges. It is generally believed
that* the Dreadnought will be assigned
v to* I the Atlantic fleet, which is the
"pivot" force of the British navy. In
the late "battle practice" the King Ed
ward VII, flagship of this fleet, when
steaming. at* fifteen knots, fired, eleven
shells from her four 12-inch guns and
hit ten /times a target distant nearly
three and a half; miles. Thirty-one
rounds were discharged with her four
9. 2 -inch guns, making fifteen hits, and
out of seventy-one rounds twenty-six
hits were scored by the 6-lnchjguns. If
the Dreadnought, with ten 12-inch guns,
equals the record the target will, under
similar conditions, be pierced twenty
times. -In addition to the Dreadnought
the Atlantic fleet will include, irrespec
tive of armored cruisers and other com
ponents and auxiliaries; seven battle
ships of the King. Edward VII type,
each mounting -four 12-inch, four 9.2
inch and, ten 6-lnch guns. Assuming
that .circumstances enabled each of
these." eight men-of-war to put in a full
broadside every minute, the following'
weight of shells would be discharged:
Pounds.
Dreadnought 6,800
Seven King Edward VITs... 51,940
Total 53,740
The calculation is based on the mod
estTassumptio^n that from. each 12-inch
gun one shell will be fired a minute,
fromeach" 9.2-inch two and from every
6-inch five,-' This* rate is frequently ex
ceeded, but it may suffice as an "average
\u25a0 fora fleetof .eight ships. -On this basis
the total 'discharge each minute from
the Atlantic fleet firing broadside-on
at "an. enemy is more^than twfcnty-'six
tons of metal. Presuming the stand
ard of the King Edward -Vll's 12-Inch
guns -is twenty-three ton 3,
would get therefore home, in the ships'
ofjahy foeUhat chanced to be the ob
jective.V"'No thing so_£ overwhelming as
this .concentrated destruction has"ever
been conceived in the brain of man. It
is impossible .to picture ;the result of.
one minute's lwell .s directed ,flre at an
\u25a0 enemy's ships, and'vwhen the 'gunners
get the range and fire as at target prac-
tlce, one minute being followed hy.
others, the effect will be annihilation.
To this length has the contest for se*
power gone, and even this la not the
end.
These possibilities result from the as
tonishing advances in heavier ordnanco.
Until within a few years the British 12
inch gun was 40 calAers in length and de
veloped a velocity of about 2500 feet
per \u25a0second. It is interesting to learn
that each of the 45-callber 12-inch euns
of the Dreadnaught is to be something
like 30 per cent more powerful than tha
12-lnch employed two years ago. It will
have double th© power of the 9.2-inch,,
nearly five times the power of tha 7.5
and eight times that of the 6-lsch. Be
tween ISD2 and 1902 the collective muzzle
energy from one round of battleship guns
Increased 22 per cent, whereas between
1902 and 1906 the advance has been 147
per cent.
Moreover, the maintenance of enerrn
and penetrative power at long range is
favored by a greater weight of projectile,
and heavy cuns have as a corollary the
advantage over light pieces. At long
ranges the improved optical devices for
sighting and range finding demanded
have been speedily provided by inventive)
Ingenuity, and this combination of tha
various devices with a natural aptitude
for. getting on the target and with a ra
tional and progressive training is pro
ducing results that are nearly marvelous.
The maximum fighting range of tha
Dreadnaughfs 12-lnch guns,' for ex
ample, is five miles, and the chances ot
hitting targets at this distance aro
auite good. "Since we have been devel
oping larger battleships," declares Cap
tain Wain wright. U. S. N., in the Pro
ceedings of the Naval Institute, "the
power of hitting with -big guns has been
Increasing. by leaps and bounds. All ord
nance material has improved, and the
training of officers and 'men; has become
scientific. Now the heaviest guns can b©
fired as rapidly as the intermediate guns
could be fired formerly, and with them,
they can make 1 more' hits than the light
er guns could make in earlier times. The
old theories of a 'smothering fire*, and 'a
greater number of units* must be allowed
to die, _as one or two hits from the big
guns can destroy soft ends and wreck
weak battery spaces, and such guns alone
are able to attack the life of the ship.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1906-05-02/ed-1/?sp=9&q=America+Dreadnought+Plans+Battleship+England+Navy&st=text&r=-0.221,-0.072,1.442,1.442,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>THINK AMERICA GOT GOTBritish GOTr OT
DREADNOUGHT PLANS PLANSBri

British Bri sh Suspect United States of Hav Having Having
ing Made Use of the Much MuchPrized
Prized Papers PapersLONDONT
LONDON LONDO May 2 iA A grave JT ve naval
scandal has developed over the myster
Joite disappearance of the plans of the thenew I
new battleship Dreadnought which was WIUlaunched I
launched only a short tlmo ago agoIt
It is believed that the plans have been beensold
sold to a a foreign power by a navy de departmeat
partment official The government has I
been trying to keep the matter quiet
but the fct has htt now transpired that
the plans disappeared a month mon th ago thaii and i
were returned to the admiralty through throughL I
the mall The power which secured the th t
plans is not known but suspicion is 18directed in I
directed toward America Qwlng to the theannouncement
announcement that the United States StatesIntends
Intends immediately to construct a a bat
tleshlp on Improved Dreadnought de designs designs
signs s nL nLThIs
This Is the most serious betrayal of ol I
British naval plans that has occurred occurrec I
In many years ears and la i a hard blow to U S
the admiralty admIraIt because of the many new newconstruction nesconstructIon
construction methods in the Dread Dreadnought Drea Dreanought Dreadnought
nought which England En land tried its hardest hardestto hardestto
to keep secret in the hope that it would wou1nput
put Great Britain several years ahead aheadot aheadof
of the other powers in the new style styleof styleot styliwarships
of warships warshipsNaval warshipsNaval warshipsNaval
Naval Authorities AuthoritiesDeny AuthoritiesDeny AuthoritiesDeny
Deny Impeachment ImpeachmentNaval
Naval authorities in Washington scoff scoffat Bcoett f fat
at t tho suggestion that the plans plansot of the theDreadnought theDreadnought thi thiDreadnought
Dreadnought were surreptitiously ob obtained obI ohtamed
tamed by thIs Government and deny denyi den1that den r rthat
that the plans of the 18000ton battle battleship
ship have In any manner been Inspected inspectedI Inspectenby
by American naval nayalarchJtects nayalarchJtectsIt architects architectsIf
If we could obtain the Dreadnought Dreadnoughtplans Dreadnoughtplans t tplans
plans In a manner free and above board boardthey hoardthey
they would be of considerable protes professional protessional
sional interest to us USU eald a naval con constructor
structor today But even 1C I we were wereso wen S Sminded
so minded I do not think It would be hI S Sworth
worth while to try to obtain them In a asneaking a asnenklng 5 5sneaking
sneaking way We believe our ability ablUt to ti
design de IEn a big bll ship Is just as great as that thatof thatot tim t</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1906-08-13/ed-1/?sp=4&q=Germanys+Battleships+Germany+Dreadnought+Naval&r=-1.462,-0.064,3.923,1.526,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>GERMANY'S BATTLESHIPS.
One of the leading naval powers which re
organized their j»olicj- promptly when the
Dreadnought was launched last February is
Germany. She has bpeu building two battle
ships a year for several years, and decided that
the next ones authorized should be a match for
the vessel now under construction at Torts
mouth. The Tribunes London correspondent
declares that the Kaiser is not entirely satis
fied with the decision reached a few months
ago. and that the Ersatz Bayern aud Ersatz
Sachaea will !>e bigger than the Dreadnought.
From other sources it is learned that these
ships will probably have a displacement of
1!».000 tons, instead of 18,0<>0 (as originally
planned), and will mount sixteen 1 1-inch guns.
The Dreadnoughts main battery is to consist
of ten 12-incfa guns.
by this news. She bus been setting tbe pace
for the rest of the world for years, and Is under
no obligation to limit herself in the future to
vessels like the Dreadnought. Nevertheless, it
would be bard to predict the outcome of an en
gagement between that particular ship and one
of tbe kind which the Kaiser now has in his
mind's The Dreadnought is expected to
be t lit* faster ship. She has Iteen designed to
develop a sptvd of "Jl knots, whereas the new
German battleships are intended to develop
tiuly IM^.. Tbe ship which can manoeuvre best
In action bas a great advantage over its ad
versary. Again, trifling as is the difference in
tbe calibre of their guns, it might have an
appreciable effect under certain conditions. Just
now everything is being sacrificed to long range,
and tbe range of a camion Is approximately
proportioned t« its bore, if it should prove that
the Dreaduought't) guns could begin the work
of destruction a few minutes earlier than those
of her enemy, thai qualification might more
than offset the ability to throw more hundred
weight of metal n minute.
It is not at all unlikely that Germany's dis
satiafaction with the plans adopted early in the
V-ar has been Inspired less by what is being
ilone by Great Britain than by hints of what
other powers luive in view. Admiral Dewey
told the House Committee <-v Naval Affairs four
or rive- months ago that lie had reason to sus
peel that Japan bad decided on 19,000-ton
battleships. Besides, while Secretary Kona
parte's plans were not perfected at that time,
it is no secret that the United States Navy De
partment wanted the privilege «.f building a
warship of greater size than any of which there
was luen any assurance. Fortunately or un
fortunately, the Secretary could not secure the
authority to proceed Quietly with the realiza
tion of thai purpose, but it is not to be supposed
that the government in Berlin was kept in
ignorance regarding bis Intentions,
Germany is now taking un exceptionally long
stride in the development of her navy. She
doubtless realizes that iv HJine respects she has
been backward, and is eager to make up for
lost time. The I'nited States has ready for ser
vice, if not actually In commission, five battle
ships displacing 15,000 tons each, and having a
spaed of 19 knots. Two vessels of the Louisiana
Ihss. displacing 16,000 tons and developing a
K|>eed of is knots, are virtually completed, and
four more are under construction. The biggest
Ships now being built for Germany have a dis
placement of 13/JUO tons. The keels of two
were laid last year, two others were launched
in iftOfi. and one of that particular class (the
Deutachland) is now finished of another
group, having a displacement of {.'mm> tons
exactly, four are ready for -service, If not in
commission, and a fifth is rapidly approaching
completion. The older German battleships are
comparable in size with thorn* of the classes to
which the Oregon, the Illinois and the Mahip be
long. Borne of them mount nothing larger than
0.4-iiicli guns, however, while the biggest guns
on American battleships Invariably nave a
calibre of 12 or IS inches. Apparently there has
been room for Improvement in the weight of
Germany's naval ordnance n« well as In tbe
pi/f» of hrr tijrliting Khip*. nnd It is by no moan*
certain that she bas fulfj awakened to her
NEW- YORK DAILY TRIBrNE. MONDAY. AIGCST 1£ 1966.
needs even yet.-" Except' for coast defence, her
heaviest guns, today ha^ve calibre of only 11
Inch*-.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045555/1906-09-15/ed-1/?sp=32&q=Keeping+Navy+Battleships+Battleship+Warship+Naval+Dreadnought&st=text&r=-0.373,-0.087,1.745,1.745,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Keeping Our Navy Up to Date
S Bifteit W mhip May Not De the Beet Our Fijhtintf Fleet Meaiures Up i
To Higheit Standard of ciencyNewest Improvements I
In Deiign and Equipment
Spedal to the N OWII
EW yom Sept IfcUnlloil
NEW nuI olllotrs do not ad
mit that the monitor tattleiihlps
pinnned by Great JJrltaln and
Italy are ntrtnmrlt lime ifTaiix
than warships of the onmitrut
Louisiana and MichiganSouth iaillm
u
type Now that fuller detail hav
reached hwc regarding the Cunlbwtl
batlloHhlp with uhteh Italy oxpecU to
oulclaits the Dreadnought there Is
leMi disposition than over to overrstl
rnaii the importancu of Italys mint I
On iiriH r ii naval HiMrurtpr nt
t8 lallo thf Krooklya Yard said tifitli
Umit Itrltaln arid Italy nlll havi slMps
greatly superior to anything In our na
vy Hut all compuil vshlrh take
into consideration merely romparatlve
displacement and battery strength oro
misleading No one know in yet how
thee monster warships will bltav 1 nt
em Thrf Dreadnought went Into
commission only two week ago and
has never Imd o trlul of any kind And
their etfeitlvonees In action Is In even
greater doubt
Moreover the assumption that the
blffgwt battleship can whip one of a
few hundred tons smaller IOOVH out of
Account the matter of wanwimlilp
bralnR courage inarkxnianhlp and
relative efficiency Amerlntn wnnthliw
may not he us big a f the IIHt but
In personnel and rqulpm nt tnty eqiul
anything alloat
This Offlxi railed allenll to the
npla menl of the lmh guns mi iKe
ttonnectlrul wlinh has been II
planned that thy haH a range of flre
L 4
from dead IIIId to a J411111 1111 beam I
Another Jnke that add vastly to th
safely IOf American ttarihlpa i the ar
rangement for elodiiB all the bulkhead I
down III time of danger From an I
emergency station on thf brldxc or In
the pIM hour all the door below the
water line in be closed almost Instant
ly by wht II known a I the loll
Arm s itni Bach IJ r and the IIr
mor liatrhM have nn electric motor
connettod with the central illation In
any emiTgemy the ship ran be rendered
IHHitlnlly UTislnknltlo In a f min
ulr hy murtlng the e mnollIlInd mak
ing Ito alerllitht toiiiiirtninH do
many life preeervsru JTwt It It no
imaginary danger agnln hlh naval
ontrutor are guarding m war
ihipe by rwrfeollmj thrtr Imlhlieid ar
nuigiminia In hue wny l nhoiitby a
liniC llnf of ii Fine dlMffr b siniins
Hllli th I of th VJriinlt and iiin
ing Ii a n the lIUIlItJai i4inff war
Other pouem are deeply Interested In
the Lone Arm nyitem but for the
present United States fighting rhlp
alone have the advantage of the most
effective means of safety devised since
the watertight bulkhead was Intro
duced
Our newt warrhtps nlw have a
uteamlng radius of 5000 miles much
greater than that of any other battle
tihlpi afloat ThiN Is a very Imiortant
element In the lighting efllclenry of all
war vessflp and ono In which the large
Knglith and Kalian battleships are like
ly to fall
Improved steering gtnr better pro
vlBton for handling iimmunlllon and
means 01 comniunteatlon far in ad
I anee of an thln r heretofore perfoeted
arc additional advantazes claimed for
Tnoie Sams latent warships on the
Innnctltiit and liuMlana a complete
IdeptMne system Is installed In ad
dillon rriMite linos are run for the ex
ecutlve odlrer navigator chlof engi
neer surgeon and electrIcal gunner
There are ii extension from the can
tral station and even private llnei In
addition to S7 linos of voice pi pea</text>
      </result>
      
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1906-10-21/ed-1/?sp=7&q=Limiting+Naval+Expansion+Dreadnought+Battleship</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>That the sinking of the French tor torpedo torpedo torjiedo
pedo submarine boat 1 Lulls LuOn and the loss lossof loaof lossof
of several live lives will 111 have Iiev a strong ten tendency t tendency n nclenc
dency clenc to discourage d JC uraae the building of o sub submarine iubmarin submarine
marin marine warcraft and result In h l more morebattleship or orbattleships i
battleship battlesll in all the navies ef the theworld tileworld theworld
world Is an opinion expressed by high highnaval Ii Iiflllvl highnvaI
naval ofQoers Q who ho have nave va studied the sub submarine JMIbmarine submarine
marine fighting proposition propositionA
A As such UCh accident a as this continue to tooccur totWcur tOoccur
occur to submarine vessels of different differentcountries dlttenmteountrl differentcountries
eountrl countries some naval officials believe believethat betlevethat believethat
that such method of warfare are arescarcely Areaearcely nm nmscarcely
scarcely practicable considering CO the thehazard thehazar th thhazarl
hazard hazar to life of tho th officers and men on onboard OKboard onboard
board Of course cou only young officers officersf officersof
of f daring disposition dt potltUon and sailors who whowould whowould u I Iwould
would readily take ke their liven in their theirhands theirhands i ihand
hands on any call are put on such uch ve vebut VeilI yes yes55Is
Mis but this set does not lessen the thepeace thetce thepence
peace casualties ca tJH ef navies naviesThe avtM ipa iparig I
The rig United State Sta Navy ha has a number numberunder numberundfr numberunder
under construction CO i1trucUon at a the present pre nL time timeOne timeOne timeOne
One was 11 recently put in commission commissionand commla commissionand lon lond
and d another IInoth notbr will be ready soon In Inview Inlew Inview
view lew of the mishaps that ave ve e occurred occurredto
to the American boats and the horribttt horribtttdisasters borrlbldl horribledisasters
disasters dl lUit8rt1 that have overtaken British BritishFrench BrltS BrltSJrIOhCh BritishFrench
French German and Rumthut nUIItJ war Vat vessels VatMis yeseels
eels of this type when all on board were werecaught werecaUAht werecaught
caught like rat rata in a trap the depart department deJNLrtment departremit
ment will likely 90 slow Iow IE b ordering nny nnymere ny nymere y yJftore
mere of them themEngland U UEnlaRd thirBnglnnd
England ha haM already called a halt bait it Itt itIs
1 t understood uad tood and her rapid stride in inthe Inthe inthe
the matter of battleship Wetlhil building is istaken 18takpl Istaken
taken by some e as indioattag IndI ttc that she sherealtees wtreal sherealises
realtees real that more money should be bespent be8feftt bespent
8feftt spent in InlMatU battleships and a d less ia iRJIIrinM ininarines sub submarine</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1906-11-16/ed-1/?sp=3&q=Japans+Afloat+Satsuma+Dreadnought+Battleship</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>JAPANS BIG SHIP AFLOAT.
The Satsuvia. Rivalling Great Brit
ain's Dreadnought, Launched.
Toklo. Nov. 15.— The first class Japanese bat
tleship Satsuma, of 19,000 tons, the first battle
ship to be launched in Japanese waters, took the
water to-day In the presence of the Emperor.
The greatest enthusiasm was manifested. The
newspapers here reflect the epoch making natur.i
of tlii event, as indicated by tho unprecedented
presence of the Emperor, and eulogize the suc
cess of the naval constructors. It is taken for
granted that the ship Is the equal, nnd perhaps
the superior, of any other warship afloat.
The Satsuma 1« the first battleship of modern
construction to be launched in Japan, and is be
lieved to be equal to the Pritish battleship
Dreadnouphi. According to th« Tokio corre
spondent of "The London Daily Telegraph," the
Satsuma embodies all the lessons of the war be
tween Japan and Russia. The woodwork on
board has been reduced to a minimum, tho ves
sel is fitted with elaborate fire apparatus, and
her upper works have been kept as clear of top
hamper as possible. The details of her con
struction follow in the main those of the Dread
nought, whose steaming capacity the Satsuma
is expected to excel.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1908-03-08/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Germanys+Naval+Monster+Launching+Nassau+Battleship+Battleships+Warship+Navy</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Launching of the Nassau At Attended Attended Attended
tended by Brilliant Assemblage As Assemblage Assemblage
semblage semblageTOTALCOST semblageTOTAL semblageTOTAL
TOTALCOST TOTAL COST TEN MILLIONS MILLIONSOTHER MilLIONSOTHER MILLIONSOTHER
OTHER GIANT BATTLESHIPS BE BEING BEING BEING
ING CONSTRUCTED CONSTRUCTEDWHhelmshaven CONSTRUCTEDWllhelmshaven CONSTRUCTEDVllhelmshaven
WHhelmshaven March 7 Germanys 7Germanysfirst 7Germany 7Germanyfirst Germanysfirst s
first mammoth warship was success successfully lIuccesstully successfully
fully launched here today and christ christened christened christened
ened Nassau by the Grand Duchess of ofBaden otBaden o oBaden
Baden Emperor William the grand grandduke grandduke gran granduke d
duke of 01 Baden Prince Henry of Prus Prussia Prussia Prussia
sia and Prince Henry of the Nether Netherlands Netherlands Netherlands
lands as well as a brilliant assem assemblage assembJag assemblage
blage of prominent officials were pres present present present
ent entWilhelm Wilhelm Von Hengstenberg lord lordlieutenant lordIIcutemnt lordlieutenant
lieutenant of HesseNassau made a aspeech aspeech aspeech
speech in which he greeted the new newvessel newvessel newvessel
vessel as a welcome addition to Ger Germanys Germnns Gernlanys
manys sea power and a defender of th thinterests the theinterests theInt e
interests Int rests of the empire empireThe empireThe empireThe
The launch of the giant battleship battleshipNassau battleshipNalsau battleshipNassau
Nassau Inaugurated a new era in the theGerman theGerman theGerman
German navy In size armament armamentepeed armamentI3peed armamentspeed
speed and installation she will be su superior sup superior
perior p rlor to any warship hitherto builtin built builtin builtIn
in Germany </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020645/1908-07-20/ed-1/?sp=3&q=naval+arms+race+1906&st=text&r=-0.267,-0.077,1.534,1.534,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>There are now the following an
nounced candldat.es Ip the race: S.
H. Dent and Thomas J. Hall, of Mont
gomery: Charles R. Brlcken,. of Lu
verne, and William .H. Samford. of
Troy. Mr. Dent hag only recently re
turned' from Denver, where he repre
sented the Second District In the Na
tional Democratic Convention.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014248/1907-01-03/ed-1/?sp=10&q=naval+arms+race+1906&st=text&r=-0.232,-0.073,1.465,1.465,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>Probably not more than one in five
I housand of those who witnessed the
Vanderbilt <'n|> race wire able to so
just wliai a rul ing car looked like after
it bad iinisbed that gruelling contest
of almost three hundred miles.
.\s soon us a. car finished, it was
whisked away to the scales and as
soon as its weight had been taken, it
was just as mysteriously taken away
and hidden in the training quarters of
its driver.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86099906/1906-09-01/ed-1/?sp=2&q=naval+arms+race+1906&st=text&r=-0.335,-0.084,1.671,1.671,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>THE BURDEN OF MILITARISM DOING THEIR DUTY.
American Expenditures Rank Next to of BrowmviHe Readers are Learn
those of England and France 'nS thc duy of e Kidneys.
Comparisons of expenditures for
military and naval purpoesby the'
five leading Powers (Russia being
excluded) made by the informa
tion bureaus of the War and Navy
Departments at Washington are
apt to shock this peace-loving Na
tion, which has been accustomed
to hold up its hands in horror of
the burden of militarism under
which Europe is staggering.
It has been impressed upon the
public mind in recent years that
our expenditures for military and
naval purposes were growing rapid-
ly, but it was not suspected that
we had, entered so'extensively into
the race for military and naval su
premacy with the European Pow- j
ers. tor the present year threat
Britain's expenditures for the army
will amount to $156,000,000.
Curiously enough France and
Germany will spend about the
same amount $158,000,000-</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99062018/1915-07-08/ed-1/?sp=7&q=naval+arms+race+1906&st=text&r=-0.283,-0.078,1.565,1.565,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>The Russian official statement is
sued yesterday said that a Russian
submarine blew up on Friday a German
warship of the Deutschland class which
was steaming at the head of a German
squadron at the entrance of Danzig
bay.
The Deutschland is a battleship of
12,997 tons displacement with a length
of 430 feet and a beam of 72 feet. Her
complement in time of peace is 729
men. The other battleships of the same
class are the Schlesien, Schleswig-Hol
stein, Hannover and Pommern. The
Deutschland was built in 1903.
DAY FOR KIDS AND VETERANS.
Cincinnati. Ohio. July 5. —Indepen-
dence day was celebrated here today
with exercises by large numbers of
school children at the public play
grounds and parks, as well as at a mass
meeting of the local members of the
Grand Army of Republic and Spanish
war veterans. The American citizen
day celebration was not generally ob
served.
NEWEST CITIZENS
LEARN OF OUTIFS
Americanization Day Through
out Country Utilized to In
struct Foreigners In
Citizenship.
New York, July 6.—This city’s offi
cial celebration of Independence day
today comprised a varied list of events
ranging from ceremonies and speech
making In City Hall park to patriotic
exercises by scores of neighborhood or
ganizations in different sections of the
city, the unfurling of a huge flag in
Broadway, numerous memorial exer
cises and athletic contests.
Features of the afternoon and eve
ning program was the Americanization
day meeting in the stadium of the Col
lege of the City of New York, where
thousands of immigrants admitted to
citizenship here within the last year
were to be addressed by federal and
state representatives, and numerous
suffrage meetings and dancing fetes in
the street 3.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063758/1906-04-17/ed-1/?sp=6&q=naval+arms+race+1906&st=text&r=-0.349,-0.085,1.698,1.698,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>Without military traininz. without
arms or equipment, purely for a mat
ter of principle, they entered upon a
struggle with the most powerful naval
and military power in Europe.</text>
      </result>
    
    </results>
  </topic>

  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-fort-sumter</id>
    <results>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83035143/1861-04-10/ed-1/?sp=4&q=Forts+supply+Sumter+SUPPLIED+WAR+supplied+SUPPLIES+war+Fort&st=text&r=0.163,0.622,0.09,0.07,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Various theories or reasons are given in newa-
Dorjera for the oresent military demonstrations.
among which is one that they were stimulated
by the results of certain late elections. Bnt this
is an error, as at the commencement' of the Ad
ministration tne president ana laoinei enter
tained tlie idea of reinforcing both Forts Sumter
and Pickens but owing to non acquaintance
with the means at the command of the Qovtrn
ment. and the condition of the country, the pros
ecution of the plana now progressing was im
practicable. In other words, it was necessary to
ascertain the extent of the etlecta bequeathed to
the President br the late Administration. It was
deemed essential to keep secret the objects of the
military movements, especially tlie sailing of ves
sels under sealed orders, as uudr the late Ad
ministration lb ere were persona who clandes
tinely communicated its purpose to tbe seces
sionist and a this frequently occurred before
the orders were reduced to omcii ions, ana ac
cording to a remark of an Ex Secretary, the Ad
ministration thus always found itself embar
rassed at the threshold. The present Adminis
tration baa limited auob knowledge to members
of the Cabinet, and perhaps several trusty offices,
and precautionary measure were taken so as to
render next to impossible acquiring iorbldden
information.</text>
      </result>
      
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83035143/1861-04-10/ed-1/?sp=4&q=Forts+supply+Sumter+SUPPLIED+WAR+supplied+SUPPLIES+war+Fort&st=text&r=-0.22,-0.072,1.441,1.441,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>However much the report of Southern designs
on Washington may be discredited, it k amened
tiat omcers high in authority are takinr precau
tionary measures for the salary of the Capitol.
The anxiety to hear from Sumter and South
ern points, where conflicts are apprehended, is
interute.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025725/1861-04-11/ed-1/?sp=2&q=supply+Forts+Supply+Sumter+supplied+war+War+supplies+Supplies+WAR+Fort&st=text&r=-0.203,-0.07,1.405,1.405,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Can it benefit a partizan administration, or
the citizens of the country Can the Federal
Government, by holding these Forts over
power the "Confederate States," and reduce
them to the condition of subject provinces,
if that be the policy Is any of these ends
to be reached by holding Sumter and Pick
ens Who is so obtuse as to believe it?
The theory of the seceded States is that
these forts belong to them, and that their oc
cupation by an authority which they do not
recognise, is an act of hostility in itself.
This theory may be altogeth r false in point
of fact, but there is no one so blind as not to
know that these people who set it up and in
dulge it will stand by it at all hazards and
to the last extremity. It is said that to
evacuate these forts would be cowardly and
dishonorable.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87076793/1861-04-12/ed-1/?sp=2&q=supply+Sumter+WAR+War+Supplies+supplies+surrender+war+Fort&st=text&r=-0.208,-0.071,1.416,1.416,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Fort Sumter.
publishea a private lettvr from a soldier
in Fort Htiinter, from which we extract
th r.iihiM
lain in rood leallh. and have been
ever aince I pot here; w o have i iionh to
al and drink, and si.lhnent to keep ui
four nuuitha, Our fuel is aiiiue, bill
that in nothlnp. The rebela think we
have In en ulle, but tin y imr any one else,
w ill ever know how iininy men we Lave
in this parrison. We hnve yot enoui;b
to hold the fort ii.iin.t the w hole South
in a boily.
Major A uderHon is a trim soldier, and
snare other officers, and the men would
die for him. t only w iah we had n chiinoe
t.iivetl.o r.iKcula h II, nml we can do
ton, lfwerver po uu t of t his fort, it
u-;H in I hi. u ill, Mi. .t'i.li ,,r ,.tir iilVl.'i-rs.
As losi'iiilinp ua men ami supplies, it it.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87076766/1861-04-13/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Sumter+Fort&st=text&r=-1.115,-0.161,3.23,3.23,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>President Lincoln just
informed Gov. Pickens and mysell that provis
ions will be sent to Fort Sumter peaceably, or
otherw ise by force. Signed,
G. T. BEAUREGARD.
No.2. Montgomery, April 10th, 1861.
To Gen. 0. T. Bkalbmiabo, Charleston: It
you have no doubt of the authorized character
of the agent who communicated to you the in
tentions of the Washington Government to sup
ply Fort Sumter by fore, you will at once de
mand its evacuation, and if this is refused, pro
ceed in such manner as you may determine to</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045160/1861-04-14/ed-1/?sp=2&q=fort+Sumter+Fort&st=text&r=-0.194,-0.069,1.389,1.389,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Our dispatch by telegraph this '.morning
from Fort Sumter are of thrilling intereat.
After a protracted cannonading and bombard
ment of tbirty-fve boars by tba Confederate
troops, Andersen's garrison capitulated about
three o'clock r. at. on yesterday, and .the
Southern flag now wave in Moodiest trlampb
from its ramparts I Federal war veaaela made
their appearance off the barber during the con
flict, and participated in tb return of fire from
Fort Sumter. There can be ao doubt of the
fact of the surrender, a a private dispatch re
ceived from Secretary Walker by a gentlemst
n tbe city, published in another roluma, amply
corroberatea it. </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014760/1861-04-15/ed-1/?sp=2&q=SUMTER+FORT+Sumter+Fort</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>have information from a reliable
onrce, that a gentleman arrived in this city
yesterday afternoon, having left Charleston on
Friday evening, and reports that, after twelve
hours firing upon Fort Sumter, there was no
sensible change in its condition.
JSP The Treasurer of South Carolina reports
the gifts of money to the State at $22,000, ol
which $10,000 were presented by the Jew
Mordecai. It is principally by jorced loans,
that the few rich men of the seceded Slates are
being bled.
X" The telegram, that Doubledny is "a ma
niac, and in irons," is interpreted by socio to
mean, that Doubleday resisted the surrender of
Fort Sumter by Major Anderson, and was put
in irons1' as a mutineer.
BBT The delay in the arrival of the" fleet nt
Charleston, which resulted from the storm, was
most opportune for the rebels, although, under
the circumstances of the short resistance made
by Fort Sumter, it did not probably change the
issue of stents.</text>
      </result>
      
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030213/1861-04-15/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Sumter+Fort&st=text&r=-0.288,-0.079,1.575,1.575,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Reliable intelligence has been received here,
giving assurance of the reénforcement of Fort
Pickens, according to the orders stated in THE
TrisUNE three weeks ago, and which have been
repeatedly denied by ignorant newsmongers.
That fort is now in condition, if properly sup-
poited by the ships of war, to make a successful
it, aud which will doubtless be enthused by the
"sews from Sumter. </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025725/1861-04-16/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Sumter+Fort&st=text&r=-0.196,-0.07,1.391,1.391,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>The
seceded States have entered with wonder-
ri cnanrv noon the labor of sustaining
their position. They have captured Fort
Sumter, which has been pionounced the
ctmnTPstFort in America. They had the
advantage and did their work with ease.-
This we consider entirely sufficient to con
vince the Administration that the Confeder
ate States are not playing a ridiculous farce
to amuse the rest of mankind, but, if forced
to carry out the programme they have al
ready determined upon and published, the
denouement will inevitably be a most serious
and real tragedy. </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84028385/1861-04-17/ed-1/?sp=2&q=FORTS+SUMTER+FORT+Sumter+Fort</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Siege of Fort Sumter.
We conJensc the following from the tel
egraphic dispatches to the Cleveland press.
On Friday, at four o'clock in tbe morning,
the rebels opened tbe fire npon Fort Sum
ter from their batteries on Sullivan Island,
Morris Island and other points. Fort
Sumter returned the fire and a brisk can
nonading was kept up on both sides through
the day.
The Herald's special dispatch of Friday,
says Fort Moultrie began the bombard
ment with two guns, to which Anderson
replied with three shots from his barbette
puns, after which the batteries at Mount
Pleasant Cuinmings' Point and the Float
ing Battery opened a brisk fire of shot and
shell. Anderson replied only at long in
tervals, until between-7 and S o'clock,
when he opened from two" tiers of guns
looking towards Moultrie and Stevens'
Battery, but up to three o'clock failed to
produce serious effect During thc great
er part of the day Anderson directed his
shots principally against Moultrie, the
Stevens and Floating Battery, and Fort
Johnson, they being the ouly ones opera
ting against him. Fifteen or eighteen
shots struck the Floating Battery without
effect Breaches were to all appearances
being made in the side of Sumter exposed
to tl.e fire. Portions of the parapettc were
destroyed, and several guns i-hot away.
Of the nineteen batteries in position on
ly seven have opened fire on Fort Sumter.
The remainder are held in reserve for the
expected flett</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn94056832/1911-10-21/ed-1/?sp=1&st=text&r=-0.313,-0.081,1.625,1.625,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>Mr. Nisbet says Ft. Sumner irri
gated products took five or six
prizes not saying anything of
the second prizes that were also
carried off.i
Dry-farmed products from Ft.
Sumner were awarded five or
six second prizes.
The car load of cantaloupes
which was distributed in Albu
querque during the fair also made
a great hit with the people from
all parts of the state and with
many from other states. No
man has ever done more for this
community than Mr. Nisbet
has and furthermore he has clone
it all with very little help.
Every year Ft. Sumner shows
the world the progress that a
griculture has done in this val
ley and it will only be a matter
of a few years before Ft. Sum
ner will be at the head of all ag
ricultural communities in the
state.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/item/sn94056832/1911-08-05/ed-1/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>FORT SUMNER
BASEBALL ITEMS
Now the boys are home things
seem different. They look like
as if they had been on an open
air excursion for their health
and for target practice. Em
iterio Anaya won the medal and
the markers board registered a
score of 5 bulls eyes for Anaya
Tom Perkins was disqualified
for using a baseball bat.
Artesia defeated Fort Sumner
by scores 10 to 0 and 11 to 0
two goose eyes.
Fort Sumner defeated Lake
wood 2 games out of 3 and Lake
Arthur 2 straights which makes
the tally of the season. Played
10, won 7 and lost 3.
Bearing in mind the lack of
practice and unfitness of home
grounds this is a very good
record for Fort Sumner only one
town, Artesia being able to
eclipse it. Roswell has paid out
over $1,000 to baseball this year
and cannot show a record like
this.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn94056832/1911-08-19/ed-1/?sp=1&st=text&r=-0.298,-0.08,1.596,1.596,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>They were the receiptants of a
chivarri at the hands of a score
or more youngsters Thursday
night at the Hotel de Camp and
from the amount of noise made
they were truly welcotned to Ft
Sumner.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn94056832/1911-05-20/ed-1/?sp=1&st=text&r=-0.289,-0.079,1.579,1.579,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>According to Ernest van Dyke,
a nephew of General B. J. Vil
joen, the general is not in any
way connected with the Mexican
revolution, the press dispatches
to the contrary, not withstand
ing. Mr. van Dyke says that
the general resides near El Paso,
and is an officer of the-New
Mexico National Guard. Being
a veteran soldier, the general
naturally would be attracted by
the war which is being conducted
practically next door to lum.
M- A. Wells and bride arrived
Friday, the 12th, from Snyder,
Okla., and are domiciled at the
Hotel de Camp. Mr. Wells was
here a short time ago and return
ed home to be married. He in
tends to engage in business here.
and they will be a welcome
addition to the business and
social circles of Ft. Sumner.
Harry Lemen, of Madison,
Ind. is in the city, enroute to
California, and spent some time
here investigating the business
prospect.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/2023271006/1942-10-23/ed-1/?sp=1&st=text&r=-0.332,-0.083,1.664,1.664,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>The drive to enlist all civilians at Fort Snelling
into spending at least 10;? of their weekly pay in to
War Bends was begun last week here on the Post,
Because of t.ie close association with Servicemen
and because of the personal relationship which many of
the civilians have with the men- they, more than any
other group know the extreme urgency of buying Car Bonds
100^ Subscription Must Be Reached.
Civilians in the industrial 'world have
ergcncy splendidly. When Fort Snelling has
quota-—it's name will be inscribed on the
of the Command.</text>
      </result>
    
    </results>
  </topic>

  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-new-york-city-flatiron-building</id>
    <results>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1902-05-17/ed-1/?sp=4&q=Flatiron+Building&st=text&r=-0.259,-0.076,1.517,1.517,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Flatiron Building May Lose Permit.
Promiscuous use of cellars ostensibly
dug for boiler rooms as business places
is going to be stopped or properly paid
for if President Cantor has his way
about it.
He is paying particular attention to
the new Platiron building, at Broadway
and Twenty-third street. He says that
if he finds that rathskellers and restau
rants are to be opened under this build
ing he will revoke the permit or make
the owners of th;e building pay the city
the proper compensation.
The Flatlron buiUling has a grand to
tal of 14,479 square feet of vaults. Presi
dent Cantor says he has ascertained
that the owners, of the Flatiron build
ing have constructed thre.? separate
stories in their vaults, a basement, cel
lar and subcellar, amounting, all told,
to 43,428 square feet for the building un
der the street line.</text>
      </result>
      
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1902-06-08/ed-1/?sp=10&q=WEEK+REALTY&st=text&r=-0.27,-0.077,1.54,1.54,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Larsre shops, such a? that in the tot.
James Building, centrally situated, have been found
to pay very well, at least as an advertisement, for
the people" who frequent middle Broadway are a.
most without exception smokers of large quantities
of tobacco, and the consequence is that such ex
pensive locations as that of the ground Boot of the
new Flatiron Building, or such as the corner or
Thlrty-second-st. and Broadway, mentioned above,
are being found to be peculiarly adapted to the to
bacco trade.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1902-06-29/ed-1/?sp=33&q=IMPRESSIVE&st=text&r=-0.335,-0.084,1.671,1.671,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>The Flatiron Building, at the intersection of
Broadway. Fifth-aye. and Twenty-third-st..
York, is a marvel of tall building construc
tion. It takes its name from the ground plan,
which roughly resembles the form of a sadiron.
Its greatest length is 190 feet En Broadway. It
is 173 feet long in Fifth-aye.. and 80 feet S
inches in Twenty-second -st Since the removal
last week of the scaffolding, which partly con
cealed the outlines, there is scarcely an hour
when a staring wayfarer doesn't by his example
collect a big crowd of other staring people.
Sometimes a hundred or more, with beads bent
backward until a general breakage of necks
seems imminent, collect along the walk on the
Fifth-aye. side of Madison Square and stay
there until "one of the finest" orders them to
till., on.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1902-07-07/ed-1/?sp=1&q=FLATIRON&st=text&r=-0.149,-0.065,1.297,1.297,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>NEW FLATIRON BUILDING ON LONG ACRE TRIANGLE
I
The Long Acre triangle nt Fortysecond street Broadway and Seventh
avenue has been purchased and leased by the George A Fuller Construc
tion Company and the Central Realty Bond and Trust Company A flat 0
Iron building similar In construction to that nearing completion on the
flatiron at Twentythird street and Broadway will be erected on the site
A morning newppaper will occupy n large portion of the building The
terms of the sale arc not stated</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062245/1902-07-20/ed-1/?sp=29&q=UNIQUE&st=text&r=-0.258,-0.076,1.516,1.516,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>A policeman got rattled on that nnat
for Just a minute the otherday Hed
been sajing Flatiron for several
hours and to the next questioner an
elderly woman from out of town he
said Laundry building by mistake
What a wash what a wash they do
have she exclaimed when aho rnt
across and began to count stories
She lost her count at the sixteenth
safe In a gale and was going round an
other way when his hat blew off and
went plum over against the rintiron he
was afraid of
It was one of those Panama hats
The fellow looked as if he wanted to
ask me to get his hat but he didnt
have the nerve for that
Finally he edged over with one eye
on Jhe flatiron and one on his Panama</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1902-07-14/ed-1/?sp=4&q=Greet+FLATIRON&st=text&r=-0.272,-0.077,1.545,1.545,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Another flatiron building, similar in
construction to that now nearing com
pletion at Broadway and Twenty-third
street, is to be erected in New York.
The site of the new building will be the
famous Longacre triangle, at Broad
way, Forty-second street and Seventh
avenue. The portion of the lot now
occupied by the Pabst hotel has been
leased for twenty-five years at an an
nual rental of $25,000, and the remain-
Ing portion has been purchased out
right by the Central Bond and Trust
company and the George A. Fuller
company. </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062245/1902-07-27/ed-1/?sp=25&q=skyscraper+flatiron&st=text&r=-0.259,-0.076,1.518,1.518,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Instead of the Outer Walls
Being the Support of
the Building They Are Now
Mcrelg Hung on the Steel
Skeleton Which Is Put Up
to the Roof Sometimes
Betore the Brick or Stone of
the First Story Is In Place
HIRTEEN rears ago there was not
a single steel frame building iii
jl the world Today there are
thousands ot them In America
alono
America has buildings which overtop
the mightiest ot the pyramids</text>
      </result>
      
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1902-11-17/ed-1/?sp=8&q=flatiron+building&st=text&r=-0.146,-0.065,1.293,1.293,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>In tho new
a Flatiron building yesterday was an Interesting and
Important demonstration of how a skyscraper may be
t equipped to extinguish fire within or repel Its Invasion
Vi from without At one time two engines attached to tho
K pipes were propelling nine powerful streams from tho
y windows of the nine upper floors the highest more than
sv three hundred feet above tho street
tSuch an equipment would have saved the tower of
the East River bridge It would have enabled the tall
Home Life building at Warren street to defend Itself</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1902-11-23/ed-1/?sp=37&q=flatiron+skyscraper&st=text&r=-0.188,-0.069,1.376,1.376,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>IhoFlatiron theFlatiron
Flatiron Building lldln at Bmadnny Un I and Inll Twentv Twentvthird TIItn TIItnthir wenty wentythird
third thir street Irel to givn gI Io e aid 011111 In IlKhtiiiK nihtl possible possibleOres poh pohfr Iatssiblfires
Ores fr in the Ip big skysctaperihn skyscraper skyscraperThe k1calc k1calclhA
The building hllllnl Is I twentytwo 11fllrIO stories pWrlf high highand hllh hllhand highand
and the Iht standpipes run 11 from tho cellar Itlar f fuv I vin i iOnu
Onu OnuBI
uv BI XKr Ws EIi HMVS JUi ro nn 111 1X1iESThe iinis iinisThe I ITe
The Te Odd Vojane CIU Uhleh a 1 llctlrrd ntrrll Sea Sr CII CIItaln yaps yapssin ai aitain
tain sin In I to Make Ikf In a Noel Craft CraftA Irlr IrlrA raft raftA
A little Itlr craft of peculiar pcullr rig rls lying 1 III at thefoot the thefoot I Il
foot of Twentyfifth Wfl I th street I rl t South Brook Brooklyn Ironl IronlII Ilrnoklyn
lyn II Is I fitting ftlu out Olt for a I voyage UI I of lOX lOXmiles 10f 10fmil IOtsmilev</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1908-03-01/ed-1/?sp=29&q=architect+flatiron</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Temple and nearly all Ole other famous famousskyscrapers t famousskyscrapers mous mousskyscrApers
skyscrapers of Chicago are his work workwhile workwhile workwhile
while the Flatiron Building Is among the thebig thebig thebig
big structures In New York for which ho hofurnished hefurnished befurnished
furnished the plans plansAs plansAs plansAs</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87065530/1952-08-22/ed-1/?sp=5&q=flatiron+1902&st=text&r=-0.214,-0.071,1.428,1.428,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Flatiron Building is observing its
50th birthday like a lonely old
freak—too short to show up on
today’s skyline, too far downtown
to have any glamor, tA6 durable
to excite alarmists any more.
Today, only a handful of tour
ists visit the 21-story building and
most of them want to go up in
the Flatiron only to take pictures
of other taller buildings.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85025570/1906-05-02/ed-1/?sp=9&q=flatiron+1902&st=text&r=-0.312,-0.081,1.625,1.625,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>He knew Mr. Man had merely drawn
:he wrong coat in the usual Clothes Lot
tery, and that its Flat-iron Faking had
just ivilied out in the recent damp
weather.
The Floorwalker was a Wise Guy and
he was used to quick thinking.
So, he said he'd just have the Bushel
man "fix" that Sore-Coat in a jiffy, so it
ODD fELLOWS JUBILATE</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016348/1905-11-11/ed-1/?sp=5&q=flatiron+1902&st=text&r=-0.316,-0.082,1.632,1.632,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>THE FLATIRON BUILDING,
teats. The r.am of this man is John
Garrick, and lie is called “The Hu
man Fly.” His oe u|iai ion is hanging
and removing awnings. To do ins work
he simply walks up mid down the out
side of buildings while other workmen
go from story to story by means of the
stairway or the el* vator.
John Garrick before ho took up the
trade of awniug hanging was a s .lor.
He followed tho s a from boyhood to
manhood, and during his service on
deep-sea sailing ships ho learned to
climb and cultivated his nerve.
A few days ago lie was engaged in
removing awnings from the Flatiron
building, mi New York. Broadway was
choked with people watching the Hu
man Fly at work. Incredible as it
may seem, lie climbed tiie sheer wad
of that building from pavement to cor
nice, two hundred and eighty-six feet
and down again.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1933-06-30/ed-1/?sp=12&q=flatiron+1902&st=text&r=-0.251,-0.075,1.501,1.501,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>FAMOUS "FLATIRON" BUILDING,
"STINGY PIECE OF PIE," ON BLOCK
Queer Structure Earned Early Fame and Has Long Been
Target of Criticizing Esthetic.
By the Associated Trtst.
NEW YORK, June 30.—The Flatlron
Building—that "stingy piece of pie"
that made some critics of 1902 moan as
If they had eaten it and got stomach
ache—went on the block today.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062245/1902-07-20/ed-1/?sp=29&q=flatiron+1902&st=text&r=-0.258,-0.076,1.516,1.516,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>A policeman got rattled on that nnat
for Just a minute the otherday Hed
been sajing Flatiron for several
hours and to the next questioner an
elderly woman from out of town he
said Laundry building by mistake
What a wash what a wash they do
have she exclaimed when aho rnt
across and began to count stories
She lost her count at the sixteenth
safe In a gale and was going round an
other way when his hat blew off and
went plum over against the rintiron he
was afraid of</text>
      </result>
    
    </results>
  </topic>

</topics>
